佛罗多！
Frodo!
不
Oh, no.
他还活着
He's alive.
我没事  我没受伤
I'm all right. I'm not hurt.
你应该没命的
You should be dead.
那一剑连野猪都能刺死
That spear would have skewered a wild boar.
小哈比人远比我们想像的厉害
I think there's more to this Hobbit than meets the eye.
秘银
Mithril.
你总是叫人吃惊  巴金斯先生
You are full of surprises, Master Baggins.
快到凯萨督姆桥！
To the Bridge of Khazad-d?m!
这边！
This way!
又来了什么怪物？
What is this new devilry?
炎魔
A Balrog.
远古的恶魔
A demon of the ancient world.
你们都不是它的对手
This foe is beyond any of you.
快跑！
Run!
快点！
Quickly!
甘道夫
Gandalf.
带领他们  阿拉贡
Lead them on, Aragorn.
桥就快到了
The bridge is near.
照我说的做！剑是无法对付炎魔的
Do as I say! Swords are no more use here.
甘道夫！
Gandalf!
梅里！皮聘！
Merry! Pippin!
山姆！
Sam!
谁也不能丢矮人
Nobody tosses a Dwarf.
别扯我的胡子！
Not the beard!
稳住
Steady.
站好！
Hold on!
稳住！
Hang on!
往前倾！
Lean forward!
稳住
Steady.
快点！
Come on!
快跳！
Now!
快过桥！
Over the bridge!
快过去！
Fly!
你不能过去！
You cannot pass!
甘道夫！
Gandalf!
我是圣火的仆人  高举着亚尔诺炽焰
I am a servant of the Secret Fire, wielder of the flame of Anor.
邪恶之火不会帮你  乌顿之火！
The dark fire will not avail you, flame of Udun!
滚回黑暗中吧
Go back to the Shadow.
你不能过去！
You shall not pass!
不！不！
No! No!
甘道夫！
Gandalf!
快走啊  你这傻瓜！
Fly, you fools!
不！
No!
阿拉贡！
Aragorn!
勒苟拉斯  把他们扶起来
Legolas, get them up.
让他们静一静吧！
Give them a moment, for pity's sake!
天一黑半兽人就会蜂拥而上
By nightfall, these hills will be swarming with Orcs.
我们一定要赶到罗斯洛立安森林
We must reach the woods of Lothlórien.
走吧  波罗莫 勒苟拉斯 金雳  把他们扶起来
Come, Boromir. Legolas. Gimli, get them up.
起来  山姆
On your feet, Sam.
佛罗多？
Frodo?
佛罗多！
Frodo!
跟紧了  小哈比人！
Stay close, young Hobbits!
听说一个大女巫住在这个树林
They say that a great sorceress lives in these woods.
一个精灵巫师...
An Elf-witch...
拥有可怕的法力
...of terrible power.
只要看她一眼...
All who look upon her...
就会被她的符咒击倒
...fall under her spell.
佛罗多！
Frodo!
然后永远消失
And are never seen again.
你的到来就像毁灭的脚步
Your coming to us is as the footsteps of doom.
你带来了巨大的邪恶  魔戒持有者
You bring great evil here, Ring-bearer.
佛罗多先生？
Mr. Frodo?
我这个矮人可不会被她轻易迷惑
Well, here's one Dwarf she won't ensnare so easily.
我有老鹰的锐眼和狐狸的耳朵
I have the eyes of a hawk and the ears of a fox.
这矮人喘气声这么大  就算在黑暗中也能射死他
The Dwarf breathes so loud, we could have shot him in the dark.
欢迎  勒苟拉斯  瑟兰督伊之子
Mae govannen,Legolas Thranduilion.
我们的远征队寻求你的帮忙  罗瑞安的哈尔达
Govannas vin gwennen le,Haldir o Lórien.
登丹人阿拉贡...
A Aragorn in Dúnedain
我们久仰你的大名
istannen le ammen
哈尔达
Haldir.
精灵真如传说中的有礼貌！
So much for the legendary courtesy of the Elves!
说我们都听得懂的话！
Speak words we can all understand!
自从黑暗时期我们就没跟矮人打过交道
We have not had dealings with the Dwarves since the Dark Days.
那你知道这些矮人会怎么说吗？
And you know what this Dwarf says to that?
我唾弃你的坟墓！
Ishkhaqwi ai durugnul!
那样很没有礼貌
That was not so courteous.
你带来了强大的邪恶力量
You bring great evil with you.
你们不能再前进了
You can go no further.
甘道夫不是白白牺牲
Gandalf's death was not in vain.
他也不会让你放弃希望
Nor would he have you give up hope.
你背负着沉重的担子  佛罗多
You carry a heavy burden, Frodo.
别再背负死亡的重担
Don't carry the weight of the dead.
你们跟我来
You will follow me.
卡拉斯加位顿
Caras Galadhon.
世界上精灵王国的中心
The heart of Elvendom on earth.
凯勒布理安王以及光明女王凯兰崔尔的国度
Realm of the Lord Celeborn and of Galadriel, Lady of Light.
敌人知道你们来到这里
The enemy knows you have entered here.
你们已经暴露了行踪
What hope you had in secrecy is now gone.
这儿只有八个人  但有九个人从瑞文戴尔出发
Eight there are here, yet nine there were set out from Rivendell.
告诉我  甘道夫呢？
Tell me, where is Gandalf?
我很想跟他说话
For I much desire to speak with him.
我很久没见过他了
I can no longer see him from afar.
灰袍巫师甘道夫并没有进入黄金森林
Gandalf the Grey did not pass the borders of this land.
他已坠入黑暗深渊
He has fallen into Shadow.
他被烈焰和黑暗吞噬
He was taken by both Shadow and flame.
魔苟斯的炎魔
A Balrog of Morgoth.
我们不小心进入摩瑞亚的陷阱
For we went needlessly into the net of Moria.
甘道夫做事一向都很小心
Needless were none of the deeds of Gandalf in life.
我们还不知道他的意图
We do not yet know his full purpose.
别让凯萨督姆的毁灭让你灰心丧志...
Do not let the great emptiness of Khazad-d?m fill your heart...
金雳  葛罗音之子
...Gimli, son of Glóin.
世上到处充满危险...
For the world has grown full of peril...
在所有的土地上...
...and in all lands...
爱都混合了悲伤
...Iove is now mingled with grief.
现在魔戒远征队会怎么样？
What now becomes of this Fellowship?
没有了甘道夫  希望也失去了
Without Gandalf, hope is lost.
这趟旅程险象环生
The quest stands upon the edge of a knife.
只要一不小心你们就会失败...
Stray but a little and it will fail...
世界末日也会降临
...to the ruin of all.
只要你们团结一致就有希望
Yet hope remains while the Company is true.
不要让你们的内心烦扰  快去休息吧...
Do not let your hearts be troubled. Go now and rest...
你们有太多的哀伤和疲惫
...for you are weary with sorrow and much toil.
今晚你们要好好睡一觉
Tonight, you will sleep....
欢迎  夏尔的佛罗多...
Welcome, Frodo of the Shire...
只有你见过邪眼！
...one who has seen the Eye!
欧络因(甘道夫)曾被西方众神派来守护东方的土地
A Olórin i yaresse Mentaner i Numeherui Tírien i Rómenóri
我们对这片土地的爱比深海还深
Melme nóren sina núra ala E?ro
悼念甘道夫的挽歌
A lament for Gandalf.
最贤明的迈雅  是什么让你离开了你热爱的土地
Maiaron i Oiosaila, Manan elye etevanne Nórie i malanelye?
他们说些什么？
What do they say about him?
我不忍心告诉你们
I have not the heart to tell you.
因为我的伤痛还未平息
For me, the grief is still too near.
我们宁愿抛弃一切选择屈服来挽留你
Ilfirin nairelma ullume nucuvalme. Nauva i nauva.
我打赌他们没有提到他放的烟火
I bet they don't mention his fireworks.
他们应该作诗来歌颂这一点
There should be a verse about them.
从古到今最棒的烟火
The finest rockets ever seen
在空中闪烁就像耀眼的星斗
They burst in stars of blue and green
这些闪闪发光的烟火
Or after thunder,
就像银河一样从天而降
silver showers
就跟天空飘下的花雨一样缤纷
Came falling like a rain of flowers
这都不足以形容它们有多壮观
Oh, that doesn't do them justice by a long road.
快休息吧
Take some rest.
这里很安全
These borders are well-protected.
我在这里无法休息
I will find no rest here.
我在头脑里听到她的声音
I heard her voice inside my head.
她提到我父亲和刚铎的灭亡
She spoke of my father and the fall of Gondor.
她对我说  即使现在仍有一线希望
She said to me, "Even now there is hope left."
但是我却看不到
But I cannot see it.
很久以来我们都没有希望
It is long since we had any hope.
我父亲是个高贵的人
My father is a noble man.
但是他的统治正在衰败...
But his rule is failing...
我们的子民也失去信心
...and our people lose faith.
他指望我能成功  我也想
He looks to me to make things right, and I would do it.
我想看到刚铎的荣耀恢复
I would see the glory of Gondor restored.
你以前见过吗  阿拉贡？
Have you ever seen it, Aragorn?
爱克西里昂的白塔
The White Tower of Ecthelion.
就像一串珍珠一样微微发光
Glimmering like a spike of pearl and silver.
塔上的旗帜随早晨的微风高高飘扬
Its banners caught high in the morning breeze.
你以前有没有...
Have you ever been called home...
被清晰的银号角声召唤回家？
...by the clear ringing of silver trumpets?
我见过那个白色城市...
I have seen the White City...
很久以前
...Iong ago.
有一天  我们将一起去那儿
One day, our paths will lead us there.
到时候塔上守卫将高喊
And the tower guard shall take up the call:
刚铎之王回来了
"The Lords of Gondor have returned."
你能看看镜子吗？
Will you look into the mirror?
我会看到什么？
What will I see?
就连最聪明的智者也不知道
Even the wisest cannot tell.
因为镜子...
For the mirror...
能显现很多事情
...shows many things.
过去的事情...
Things that were...
现在的事情...
...things that are...
还有一些事情...
...and some things...
尚未发生
...that have not yet come to pass.
我知道你看到什么
I knowwhat it is you saw.
因为它一样也在我心里呈现
For it is also in my mind.
如果你失败就会发生这些事
It is what will come to pass if you should fail.
远征队已经开始四分五裂
The Fellowship is breaking. It is already begun.
他会试图抢走魔戒
He will try to take the Ring.
你知道我说的是谁
You know of whom I speak.
他们会一个接一个被魔戒击垮
One by one, it will destroy them all.
只要你开口...
If you ask it of me...
我就把至尊魔戒给你
... I will give you the One Ring.
你肯毫无条件地给我
You offer it to me freely.
我承认我很渴望魔戒
I do not deny that my heart has greatly desired this.
我将成为魔戒之后
In place of a Dark Lord, you would have a queen...
她并不黑暗而是美丽得跟曙光一样耀眼！
...not dark but beautiful, and terrible as the dawn!
跟海洋一样高深莫测！
Treacherous as the sea!
远比土地更加坚强！
Stronger than the foundations of the earth!
世人都将迷恋我...
All shall love me...
而且自暴自弃
...and despair.
我通过了考验
I pass the test. I will diminish...
我将退隐到西方...
...and go into the West...
继续当凯兰崔尔女王
...and remain Galadriel.
我一个人无法摧毁它
I cannot do this alone.
你是魔戒持有者  佛罗多  持有至尊魔戒...
You are a Ring-bearer, Frodo. To bear a Ring of Power...
注定孤单一人
...is to be alone.
这是南雅  钻石之戒
This is Nenya, the Ring of Adamant.
我是它的守护者
And I am its keeper.
这个任务指派给你
This task was appointed to you.
如果你办不到...
And if you do not find a way...
没有人可以
...no one will.
我知道该怎么做了
Then I know what I must do.
只是...
It's just...
我感到害怕
...I'm afraid to do it.
即使再渺小的人也能改变未来
Even the smallest person can change the course of the future.
你知道半兽人是怎么来的吗？
Do you know how the Orcs first came into being?
它们曾经是精灵
They were Elves once.
但是却被黑暗力量...
Taken by the Dark Powers...
折磨到不成人形
...tortured and mutilated.
它们是被扭曲的可怕生物
A ruined and terrible form of life.
而现在...
And now...
变得完美
...perfected.
我的强兽人战士...
My fighting Uruk-hai...
你的主人是谁？
...whom do you serve?
萨鲁曼！
Saruman!
猎杀他们  找不到绝不罢手
Hunt them down. Do not stop until they are found.
你们没有痛苦  你们没有恐惧
You do not know pain. You do not know fear.
你们只会杀人！
You will taste Man-flesh!
有一个半身人手中有宝物
One of the halflings carries something of great value.
我要你毫发无伤地活抓他们
Bring them to me alive and unspoiled.
杀了其他人
Kill the others.
我们从来没有让外人穿上我们精灵的装束
Never before have we clad strangers in the garb of our own people.
希望这些精灵斗篷能让你们躲过敌人的侦察
May these cloaks help shield you from unfriendly eyes.
兰巴斯
Lembas.
精灵的干粮
Elvish waybread.
只要咬一小口就能让一个成年人填饱肚子
One small bite is enough to fill the stomach of a grown man.
你吃了几块？
How many did you eat?
四块
Four.
你们每向南方走一步就离危险更近一步
Every league you travel south, the danger will increase.
魔多的半兽人占领了安都因河东岸
Mordor Orcs now hold the eastern shore of the Anduin.
但是西岸也并不安全
Nor will you find safety on the western bank.
奇怪的白掌部队曾经出没在我们的边界
Strange creatures bearing the White Hand have been seen on our borders.
半兽人不能在太阳下行动  但是这些怪物却可以
Seldom do Orcs journey in the open under the sun, yet these have done so.
他们在追杀你们
You are being tracked.
只有走水路才有可能赶在敌人前到达拉洛斯瀑布
By river you have the chance of outrunning the enemy to the Falls of Rauros.
我送你的礼物  勒苟拉斯  是凯兰崔姆弓箭
My gift for you, Legolas, is a bow of the Galadhrim.
能让你拥有百步穿杨的绝技
Worthy of the skill of our woodland kin.
这些是诺多伦短剑
These are the daggers of the Noldorin.
曾经在战场上杀敌无数
They have already seen service in war.
千万别害怕  小皮里格林·图克
Do not fear, young Peregrin Took.
你会找到你的勇气
You will find your courage.
送给你的  山姆卫斯·詹吉
And for you, Samwise Gamgee...
希斯蓝制作的精灵之绳
...Elven rope made of hithlain.
谢谢你  女王
Thank you, my lady.
那些漂亮的短剑没有了吗？
Have you run out of those nice, shiny daggers?
那么矮人向精灵要什么礼物？
And what gift would a dwarf ask of the Elves?
什么都不要
Nothing.
我再看凯兰崔尔女王最后一眼就足够了
Except to look upon the lady of the Galadhrim one last time...
因为她比地底蕴藏的所有珠宝都美丽
...for she is more fair than all the jewels beneath the earth.
实际上...
Actually...
我是有一个要求
There was one thing.
不  不  我不能  那太不可能了
No, no, I couldn't. It's quite impossible.
说出来太傻了
Stupid to ask.
我不能再给你什么
I have nothing greater to give...
因为你已拥有最珍贵的礼物
...than the gift you already bear.
那就是亚玟的爱
Am meleth d?n.
我怕亚玟·安多米尔的光芒会黯淡
I ant e-guil Arwen Undómiel…pelitha.
所以我要让她离开中土世界
Aníron i e broniatha,
跟她的族人在一起
ad ae periatham athar i methid en-amar hen.
我会让她坐船到瓦林诺
Aníron i e círatha na Valannor.
她必须面对这个抉择
That choice is yet before her.
你也必须做出决定  阿拉贡
You have your own choice to make, Aragorn.
重建自伊兰迪尔以来你的先祖创造的辉煌成就
To rise above the height of all your fathers since the days of Elendil...
或是带着你仅存的子民坠入绝望的黑暗深渊
...or to fall into darkness with all that is left of your kin.
永别了
Namárie.
还有很多你要做的事情
Nadath na i moe cerich.
我们将不会再见面...
Dan ú-'eveditham
伊力萨
Elessar.
再会了  佛罗多·巴金斯
Farewell, Frodo Baggins.
我送给你埃兰迪尔之光...
I give you the light of E?rendil...
我们最挚爱的星辰
...our most beloved star.
愿它在所有光亮熄灭时...
May it be a light for you in dark places...
在黑暗中为你带来光明
... when all other lights go out.
这次离别带给我的伤痛最深...
I have taken my worst wound at this parting...
因为这是我最后一次看到最美丽的女王
...having looked my last upon that which is fairest.
以后我不会说什么东西美丽除了她的礼物
Henceforth I will call nothing fair unless it be her gift to me.
她送你什么礼物？
What was her gift?
我向她要一根她头上的金发
I asked her for one hair from her golden head.
她给了我三根
She gave me three.
咕噜  他从摩瑞亚矿坑一直在跟踪我们
Gollum. He has tracked us since Moria.
我以为在河上就能甩掉他
I had hoped we would lose him on the river.
可是他的水性很好
But he's too clever a waterman.
如果他把我们的行踪告诉敌人
And if he alerts the enemy to our whereabouts...
我们想要渡河就会更危险
...it will make the crossing even more dangerous.
吃点东西吧  佛罗多先生
Have some food, Mr. Frodo.
不要  山姆
No, Sam.
你一整天都没吃过东西
You haven't eaten anything all day.
你也睡得很不安稳  别以为我没注意到
You're not sleeping, neither. Don't think I haven't noticed.
佛罗多先生...
Mr. Frodo--
我很好
I'm all right.
你并不好
But you're not.
我是来帮你的
I'm here to help you.
我答应甘道夫我会的
I promised Gandalf that I would.
你帮不了我  山姆
You can't help me, Sam.
这次不行
Not this time.
去睡吧
Get some sleep.
到米那斯提力斯比较安全
Minas Tirith is the safer road.
我们可以在那里养精蓄锐
You know that. From there we can regroup.
然后一鼓作气攻向魔多
Strike out for Mordor from a place of strength.
刚铎也帮不了我们
There is no strength in Gondor that can avail us.
你倒是很愿意相信精灵
You were quick enough to trust the Elves.
你对自己的子民一点信心都没有吗？
Have you so little faith in your own people?
对  他们是很软弱  他们意志薄弱
Yes, there is weakness. There is frailty.
但是人类之中也有勇气和荣誉
But there is courage also, and honor to be found in Men.
可是你都看不到
But you will not see that.
你很害怕！
You are afraid!
你这辈子都躲在阴影下
All your life, you have hidden in the shadows.
不敢承认你自己的身份
Scared of who you are, of what you are.
我不会把魔戒带到你的城市
I will not lead the Ring within a hundred leagues of your city.
佛罗多
Frodo.
亚苟那斯巨像
The Argonath.
我一直都想仰望的老国王
Long have I desired to look upon the kings of old.
我的先祖
My kin.
天一黑我们就渡湖
We cross the lake at nightfall.
把船藏好再步行
Hide the boats and continue on foot.
我们从北边进入魔多
We approach Mordor from the North.
是吗？
Oh, yes?
只要通过爱明莫尔就行了...
Just a simple matter of finding our way through Emyn Muil...
那是充满尖石的迷宫
...an impassable labyrinth of razor-sharp rocks.
然后呢  就更好走了
And after that, it gets even better.
那儿有一望无际的臭沼泽地
Festering, stinking marshland as far as the eye can see.
那就是我们的路
That is our road.
我建议你休息一下养精蓄锐  矮人大师
I suggest you take some rest and recover your strength, Master Dwarf.
养精蓄锐个头
Recover my--
我们应该马上走
We should leave now.
不行
No.
半兽人在巡逻东岸  我们一定要等到天黑再出发
Orcs patrol the eastern shore. We must wait for cover of darkness.
我担心的不是东岸
It is not the eastern shore that worries me.
我心中一直有一个阴影和威胁
A shadow and a threat has been growing in my mind.
有什么正在接近  我感觉得到
Something draws near. I can feel it.
养精蓄锐？别理他  小哈比人
Recover strength? Pay no heed to that, young Hobbit.
佛罗多呢？
Where's Frodo?
我们都不该一个人乱跑
None of us should wander alone.
尤其是你
You, least of all.
你的责任重大
So much depends on you.
佛罗多？
Frodo?
我知道你为什么想独自待着
I know why you seek solitude.
我每天都看着你受苦
You suffer. I see it day by day.
你确定你不是白白受苦吗？
You sure you do not suffer needlessly?
还有其它的路  佛罗多
There are other ways, Frodo.
我们可以走另一条路
Other paths that we might take.
我知道你想说什么
I know what you would say.
好像很有道理  但我得到警告
It would seem like wisdom but for the warning in my heart.
警告？警告什么？
Warning? Against what?
我们都很害怕  佛罗多
We're all afraid, Frodo.
但如果让恐惧摧毁一切希望...
But to let that fear drive us, to destroy what hope we have...
未免太不值得了吧？
...don't you see that is madness?
没有别的路可走
There is no other way.
我只想得到捍卫我的子民的力量！
I ask only for the strength to defend my people!
只要你把魔戒借给我
lf you would but lend me the Ring.
不行
No.
为什么你要退缩？我又不是强盗
Why do you recoil? I am no thief.
你失去了理智
You are not yourself.
你以为你有什么机会？
What chance do you think you have?
他们会找到你  他们会抢走魔戒
They will find you. They will take the Ring.
然后你会求生不能 求死不得！
And you will beg for death before the end!
你这傻瓜！
You fool!
你只是靠运气得到它！它应该是我的
It is not yours, save by unhappy chance! It could have been mine.
它应该是我的！把它给我！
It should be mine! Give it to me!
把它给我！
Give it to me!
不！
No!
把它给我！
Give it to me!
不！
No.
我知道了
I see your mind.
你会把魔戒交给索伦！
You will take the Ring to Sauron!
你会背叛我们！
You will betray us!
你会害我们跟你一起死！
You'll go to your death, and the death of us all!
诅咒你！诅咒你和所有的半身人！
Curse you! Curse you and all the halflings!
佛罗多？
Frodo?
佛罗多
Frodo.
我做了什么？
What have I done?
求求你  佛罗多
Please, Frodo.
佛罗多  对不起！
Frodo, I'm sorry!
佛罗多？
Frodo?
它蛊惑了波罗莫
It has taken Boromir.
魔戒呢？
Where is the Ring?
别过来！
Stay away!
佛罗多！
Frodo!
我发誓要保护你
I swore to protect you.
你能保证你不会害我吗？
Can you protect me from yourself?
你会摧毁它吗？
Would you destroy it?
阿拉贡
Aragorn.
伊力萨
Elessar.
我愿意跟随你到最后
I would have gone with you to the end.
跟随到魔多烈焰
Into the very fires of Mordor.
我知道了
I know.
好好照顾他们  尤其是山姆  他不会理解
Look after the others. Especially Sam. He will not understand.
快走  佛罗多！
Go, Frodo!
快跑
Run.
快跑！
Run!
佛罗多先生！
Mr. Frodo!
找到半身人！
Find the halfling!
伊兰迪尔！
Elendil!
阿拉贡  快走！
Aragorn, go!
佛罗多！
Frodo!
躲过来  快！
Hide here. Quick!
快啊！
Come on!
他在干嘛？
What's he doing?
他要走了
He's leaving.
不！
No!
皮聘！
Pippin!
跑  佛罗多  快跑！
Run, Frodo. Go on!
嘿！嘿  你！我在这里！
Hey! Hey, you! Over here!
嘿！
Hey!
我在这里！
Over here!
这里啊！
This way!
成功了！
It's working!
我知道啦！快跑！
I know it's working! Run!
刚铎的号角
The horn of Gondor.
波罗莫
Boromir.
跑！快跑！
Run!
不
No.
他们把小个子抓走了
They took the little ones.
别动
Hold still.
佛罗多  佛罗多在哪里？
Frodo. Where is Frodo?
我让佛罗多走了
I let Frodo go.
你做到我做不到的事
Then you did what I could not.
我试图抢走魔戒
I tried to take the Ring from him.
现在谁也抢不走魔戒了
The Ring is beyond our reach now.
原谅我
Forgive me.
我没有想到
I did not see it.
我让大家失望了
I have failed you all.
不  波罗莫
No, Boromir.
你很英勇
You fought bravely.
你维护了你的荣誉
You have kept your honor.
算了
Leave it.
都结束了
It is over.
人类世界将灭亡  黑暗将笼罩大地...
The world of Men will fall. And all will come to darkness...
我的城市将遭毁灭
...and my city to ruin.
我不知道我有多少力量...
I do not know what strength is in my blood...
但我发誓绝不会让白城沦陷...
...but I swear to you, I will not let the White City fall...
也不会让我们的子民失败
...nor our people fail.
我们的子民
Our people.
我愿跟随你  我的兄弟
I would have followed you, my brother.
我的领袖
My captain.
我的国王
My king.
安息吧...
Be at peace...
刚铎之子
...son of Gondor.
他们在白塔等待他的归来
They will look for his coming from the White Tower.
但是他永远不会回去了
But he will not return.
佛罗多！
Frodo!
我真希望魔戒没在我手中
I wish the Ring had never come to me.
真希望这一切都没发生
I wish none of this had happened.
每个人遇到难关都会这么想...
So do all who live to see such times...
但是那不由我们决定
...but that is not for them to decide.
我们所能决定的是...
All you have to decide...
在给予我们的时间内去做什么
...is what to do with the time that is given to you.
佛罗多  不要走！
Frodo, no!
佛罗多！
Frodo!
佛罗多先生！
Mr. Frodo!
不 山姆
No, Sam.
回去吧  山姆！
Go back, Sam!
我要独自去魔多
I'm going to Mordor alone.
你当然要去
Of course you are.
但我要跟你一起去！
And I'm coming with you!
你不会游泳！
You can't swim!
山姆！
Sam!
我许下一个承诺  佛罗多先生
I made a promise, Mr. Frodo.
一个承诺  千万别离开他  山姆卫斯·詹吉
A promise: "Don't you leave him, Samwise Gamgee."
我绝不会离开你
And I don't mean to.
绝对不会
I don't mean to.
山姆
Sam.
来吧
Come on.
快！佛罗多和山姆就快到东岸了
Hurry! Frodo and Sam have reached the eastern shore.
你不想跟着他们
You mean not to follow them.
佛罗多的命运已经不由我们掌握
Frodo's fate is no longer in our hands.
一切都是徒劳  远征队失败了
Then it has all been in vain. The Fellowship has failed.
只要我们彼此真诚就不是徒劳
Not if we hold true to each other.
我们不会丢下梅里和皮聘让他们受苦而死
We will not abandon Merry and Pippin to torment and death.
只要我们还有力气
Not while we have strength left.
把用不着的东西留下来
Leave all that can be spared behind.
我们轻装而行
We travel light.
让我们猎杀半兽人吧
Let us hunt some Orc.
好！
Yes!
魔多
Mordor.
希望其他人走的路比较安全
I hope the others find a safer road.
神行客会照顾他们的
Strider will look after them.
我想我们不会再见到他们了
I don't suppose we'll ever see them again.
也许还会  佛罗多先生
We may yet, Mr. Frodo.
也许会
We may.
山姆...
Sam...
我很高兴你和我一起
...I'm glad you are with me.
但愿有一颗暮色之星
may it be an evening star
拂照着你
shines down upon you
但愿黑暗降临时
may it be when darkness falls
你的心能够真诚
your heart will be true
你孤独地上路
you walk a lonely road
噢  离家的路途有多远
oh, how far you are from home
黑暗已经降临
mornie utúlie(darkness has come)
相信你就会找到你的路
believe and you will find your way
黑暗已经降临
mornie utúlie(darkness has come)
如今希望在你心中不泯
a promise lives within you now
但愿阴影的笼罩
may it be shadows call
将消逝
will fly away
但愿你脚下的旅途
may it be your journey on
走向光明的天日
to light the day
当黑夜逝去时
when the night is overcome
愿你起身迎接朝阳
you may rise to find the sun
黑暗已经降临
mornie utúlie(darkness has come)
相信你就会找到你的路
believe and you will find your way
黑暗已经降临
mornie utúlie(darkness has come)
如今希望在你心中不泯
a promise lives within you now
当冬天的寒冷来临
When the cold of winter comes
没有星光的夜晚将遮蔽天日
Starless night will cover day
在太阳的面纱里
In the veiling of the sun
我们将在苦涩的雨中前行
We will walk in bitter rain
但在梦中
But in dreams
我依然能听到你的名字
I still hear your name
而在梦中
And in dreams
我们会再次相见
We will meet again
当大海和巍山瓦解
When the seas and mountains fall
我们会来到时日的尽头
And we come to end of days
在黑暗中我听到一声呼唤
In the dark I hear a call
呼唤我去那里
Calling me there
我会去那里
I will go there
而后复返
And back again